{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which one of the following statements is not correct for heading and benching method of tunnelling ?", "opta": "Drilling and mucking can be done simultaneously", "optb": "Benching provides a plateform for working on heading", "optc": "Removal of muck from the heading is very easy", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference of heights of the tunnels above rail tops of BG and MG tracks is kept", "opta": "0.30 m", "optb": "0.45 m", "optc": "0.60 m", "optd": "0.75 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of drift method of tunnelling, the drift may be excavated at", "opta": "the centre", "optb": "the bottom", "optc": "the top", "optd": "the side", "opte": "All of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A tunnel is found more advantageous as compared to the alternate routes because it:", "opta": "remains free from snow", "optb": "reduces the cost by reducing the route distance", "optc": "reduces the maintenance cost", "optd": "avoids interference with surface rights", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For B.G. single track railway, the height of the tunnel above top of rails should be", "opta": "5.5 m to 5.8 m", "optb": "5.8 m to 6.2 m", "optc": "6.7 m to 7.3 m", "optd": "7.3 m to 7.5 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement regarding drilling a tunnel from the following:", "opta": "Holes are drilled by pneumatically operated rock drills", "optb": "One drill is required for each 4 to 5 m2 force area", "optc": "The diameter of the bore hole at the deepest point should be 6 mm more than the diameter of the cartridge", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For tunnels exceeding 300 m in length, the grade should be provided below", "opta": "50% of the ruling gradient", "optb": "60% of the ruling gradient", "optc": "75% of the ruling gradient", "optd": "80% of the ruling gradient.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The method of draining in the tunnels, is generally known as", "opta": "foredrainage", "optb": "dewatering", "optc": "permanent drainage", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following during tunnel excavation,", "opta": "Oxygen should not be less than 19.5%", "optb": "Carbondioxide should not be more than 0.5%", "optc": "Hydrogen sulphide should not be more than 0.001%", "optd": "Carbon mono-oxide should not be more than 0.01%", "opte": "All of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To attain the required shape of the tunnel section, we use :", "opta": "easers", "optb": "trimmers", "optc": "cut holes", "optd": "chisels.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most commonly adopted pattern of cut holes is :", "opta": "horizontal wedge cut", "optb": "pyramid cut", "optc": "fan cut", "optd": "V-cut", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following linings is suitable for shield driven tunnels particularly in the subaqueous regions :", "opta": "Brick lining", "optb": "stone lining", "optc": "timber line", "optd": "cast iron lining", "opte": "concrete lining.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of railways,", "opta": "a detour round the hill is preferred", "optb": "a open cut is preferred", "optc": "tunnelling is preferred", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following tunnels were constructed in different countries for different purposes : 1. Emperor Claudius built the first Roman tunnel2. The first highway tunnel was constructed in Hungary3. The first underground railway tunnel was constructed in Great Britain4. The first navigational tunnel was constructed in France.The correct chronological development of these tunnels is:", "opta": "4 1 3 2", "optb": "1 4 2 3", "optc": "2 3 1 4", "optd": "3 2 4 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following operations are generally employed for tunnelling in hard rock. 1. Removing ground water, 2. Loading holes and firing the explosive3. Setting up and drilling4. Grouting and lining5. Removing muck6. Ventilation and removing explosion dustThe correct sequence is :", "opta": "3 2 6 5 1 4", "optb": "3 4 6 1 5 2", "optc": "4 1 2 3 6 5", "optd": "5 4 2 1 3 6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the mechanical ventilation method used for tunnels from the following:", "opta": "blowing fresh air by ducts to the face of tunnel", "optb": "exhausting foul air by ducts from the face of the tunnel and permitting fresh air through the tunnel", "optc": "blowing fresh air and exhausting foul air by ducts", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following methods of tunnelling does not require the use of time bearing :", "opta": "Linear plate method", "optb": "Shield method", "optc": "Compressed air method", "optd": "Mechanical tunneler i.e. mole method", "opte": "All the these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For highways, tunnelling is preferred to if the open cut exceeds :", "opta": "10 metres depth", "optb": "15 metres depth", "optc": "20 metres depth", "optd": "25 metres depth.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following operations are required for tunnelling in rocky terrain :1. Removing the foul gases2. Marking the tunnel profile3. Setting up and drilling4. Checking misfire5. MuckingThe correct sequence is :", "opta": "1 2 3 4 5", "optb": "2 3 5 4 1", "optc": "4 2 1 3 5", "optd": "2 3 1 4 5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The advantages of providing a pair of tunnels as compared to only one large highway tunnel is :", "opta": "economy in cost of construction", "optb": "avoidance of head on collisions", "optc": "provision of separate exit and entrance of two traffic streams", "optd": "facility in carrying out repairs", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following statements is not correct in respect of setting of an inclined tunnel:", "opta": "Reference points are constructed at every 300 m.", "optb": "The alignment is fixed from upper/lower apex point.", "optc": "The level of the invert at the heading is marked by a tape.", "optd": "Reference points are constructed on the roof of tunnels", "opte": "None the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Forepoling method is generally adopted for tunnelling in :", "opta": "soft ground", "optb": "firm ground", "optc": "running ground", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concrete lining is provided concurrently with the driving operation in case of", "opta": "rock terrain", "optb": "soft rock", "optc": "running soil", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The concentration of the dust particles of the size 0.5 to 5 microns adjacent to the working face should not be more than", "opta": "200 particles/cm3", "optb": "250 particles/cm3", "optc": "300 particles/cm3", "optd": "450 particles/cm3", "opte": "400 particles/cm3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following statements is not correct with regard to heading and hench-ing method of tunnelling.", "opta": "Driving of tunnel is done in two portions of its section", "optb": "Driving the top portion is done in advance of the bottom portion.", "optc": "After driving the top portion 3 m to 3.5 m holes are drilled into the head and bench.", "optd": "The holes in head and bench are loaded together with explosive for blasting.", "opte": "Firing of head holes is done just before the bench holes are fired.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following methods is generally used for the layout of the muck-car tracks", "opta": "the grass hopper method", "optb": "passing track method", "optc": "the cherry picker", "optd": "California crossing, Dixon conveyor", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For transferring the tunnel alignment through shafts, we adopt the following steps :1. Hanging two or more plumb lines in the shaft2. Determining the bearing of the plumb lines i.e. plumb plane3. Suspending a 35 kg weight by each plumb line4. Immersing the weights of both the plumb lines in the buckets containing water.The correct sequence of steps is :", "opta": "1 2 3 4", "optb": "4 3 2 1", "optc": "l 3 2 4", "optd": "2 1 4 3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For initial surveys of tunnels, the following activities are involved:1. Marking portal point with concrete pillars on the ground2. Marking tunnel obligatory points on the topographical maps3. Preliminary setting of the tunnel on the topographical Survey of India maps3. Driving lines between the fixed obligatory points.The correct sequence of the activities is :", "opta": "3 2 4 1", "optb": "1 2 3 4", "optc": "4 3 1 2", "optd": "2 4 3 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For full face method, the excavation to be done is generally divided into", "opta": "two sections", "optb": "three sections", "optc": "four sections", "optd": "five sections.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tunnels, the artificial underground passages are constructed for :", "opta": "highways", "optb": "railways", "optc": "sewerage", "optd": "water supply project", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the wooded bulk-head, used for mucking in steep grade tunnels,", "opta": "one opening is provided", "optb": "two openings are provided", "optc": "three openings are provided", "optd": "no opening is provided.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Railway tunnels, are generally", "opta": "polycentric", "optb": "rectangular", "optc": "parabolic", "optd": "circular", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the explosive used for tunnelling in soft rocks from the following :", "opta": "blasting gelatine", "optb": "special gelatine", "optc": "ammonia dynamite", "optd": "semi-gelatine.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cut of a tunnel face is shown in given figure. This is called", "opta": "Michigan cut", "optb": "Burn cut", "optc": "Fan cut", "optd": "Horizontal cut.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For B.G. single track, the section of the tunnel must have a width", "opta": "4.2 m to 4.5 m", "optb": "4.5 m to 4.8 m", "optc": "4.9 m to 5.5 m", "optd": "5.5 m to 5.8 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following methods is generally adopted for tunnelling in firm ground", "opta": "Full face method", "optb": "Top heading and benching method", "optc": "Drift method", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An overhead track on a large truss frame is required in case of car changer by", "opta": "the grass hopper method", "optb": "the passing track method", "optc": "California crossing method", "optd": "Dixon conveyor method.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The topographical maps of the Survey of India are useful in the mountainous region for tunnelling.", "optb": "The height point on the ridge is fixed with the help of reciprocal ranging", "optc": "The accuracy of 1 in 10, 000 is required for planimetric control", "optd": "1 second theodolite is used for angular measurement to achieve an angular error of 15 N where N is number of angles", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given figure drill holes, heading, mucking and benching are mumbered as 1, 2, 3, 4 The correct sequence is :", "opta": "4 1 2 3", "optb": "1 2 3 4", "optc": "4 1 3 2", "optd": "3 4 1 3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The length of the needle beam used in needle beam method of tunnelling is usually", "opta": "2 m to 4 m", "optb": "2.5 m to 6 m", "optc": "4 m to 7 m", "optd": "5 m to 6 m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High pressure grouting is generally restored for concreting in the lining if the rock strata is:", "opta": "highly fissured", "optb": "poor", "optc": "likely to get seepage of water", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For hauling muck from the tunnel, the following type of muck-car is used :", "opta": "muck box", "optb": "balle-ship", "optc": "side dump car", "optd": "U-bottom", "opte": "All of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following methods is adopted for permanent drainage of tunnels :", "opta": "provision of longitudinal drains", "optb": "continuous open drains", "optc": "concrete lining", "optd": "grouting with cement or chemicals", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}